

## PERSONAL BACKGROUND

I am a digital marketing specialist. I have a total of 8 years experience in being an SEO specialist, copywriter and content strategist for different digital marketing agencies and companies based in the US, Australia and Ireland. I also have a Masters in Public Administration. I have worked in various fields as a writer, researcher and assistant.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am highly adaptable and flexible to any tasks. I am a fast learner and have considerable experience in the area of SEO, Copywriting, Content Strategy, Research, Social Media Management, Content Writing, and Website Optimisation.

## **SKILLS**

- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)- Semrush, UberSuggest, Yoast and SurferSEO
- WordPress proficient
- Knows how to use Microsoft Office, Google Office, Slack, Canva, Asana, ClickUp, Trello, Monday, Notion, Zoom, HubStaff, and other productivity tools

## **LANGUAGES**

- Filipino
- · English
- Bicol
- Basic Mandarin Chinese

## GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

- Phone: +63 917 150 75 84
- Email: labortelovelymae@gmail.com
- Facebook: Le Lovely Mae Laborte
- Skype: Lei Laborte

# LOVELY MAE LABORTE

Digital Marketing and SEO Specialist

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Digital Marketing and SEO Specialist**

#### ScrewLooselt Digital | July 2023-March 2024

- Site audit and analysis including SEO project viability
- Keyword research in alignment with product/service
- Executes entire on-page and technical set/optimisation (URL, meta data, on-page content, semantic links etc.)
- Propose best content for on-page and new page site additions to support keyword goals and objectives
- Creates copy and delivers content on Wordpress
- Continually analyse and propose keyword and content opportunities
- Analyse page experience (structure & design inline with site/page objectives) ensuring high-quality user engagement
- · Resolves SEO issues monthly
- · Overall ensures keyword rankings trend up

# **Copywriter and Social Media Manager**

#### Self Build 3D | February 2022-November 2023

- Creates and schedules content for Instagram and Facebook groups and pages
- Ensures 300,000-600,000 engagement rate per week
- Researches on potential posts and identifies potential clients

# **Lead Content Strategist and Website Copywriter**

# RJW Digital | July 2021-present

- Assists CEO in his tasks to grow the company
- Manages a team of writers for blog writing and web copies
- Creates website copies and landing pages for different clients
- Edits and revises different social media calendars with the social media manager
- Works in SurferSEO to ensure copies will rank highly among competitors
- Schedules and posts blogs using Wordpress

# **Copywriter and SEO Specialist**

#### Cool Pixels | July 2021-present

- Assists the founder of the National Association for Kidpreneurs (NAK)
- Plans for NAK Instagram Calendar
- Reaches out and sends letters to different US local government units (mayors and governors) for support on National Kidpreneur Day
- Creates landing page copies and Google Ad copies (text and display)
- · Writes testimonials and reviews
- SEO-optimised website content (Home, About Us, Services, etc...)

#### Get Gladified | July 2021- September 2021

- Writes content for newsletters and website copies
- Writes captions for social media posts of clients

#### Boom Now Inc. | Feb 2020- June 2022

- Writes content for LinkedIn profiles and blogs for B2B clients
- Creates and checks content for SEO for some clients
- Responsible for press releases and monthly reports
- Writes captions for social media posts of clients



## PERSONAL BACKGROUND

I am a digital marketing specialist. I have a total of 8 years experience in being an SEO specialist, copywriter and content strategist for different digital marketing agencies and companies based in the US, Australia and Ireland. I also have a Masters in Public Administration. I have worked in various fields as a writer, researcher and assistant.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am highly adaptable and flexible to any tasks. I am a fast learner and have considerable experience in the area of SEO, Copywriting, Content Strategy, Research, Social Media Management, Content Writing, and Website Optimisation.

## **SKILLS**

- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)- Semrush, UberSuggest, Yoast and SurferSEO
- WordPress proficient
- Knows how to use Microsoft Office, Google Office, Slack, Canva, Asana, ClickUp, Trello, Monday, Notion, Zoom, HubStaff, and other productivity tools

## **LANGUAGES**

- Filipino
- English
- Bicol
- Basic Mandarin Chinese

## GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

- Phone: +63 917 150 75 84
- Email: labortelovelymae@gmail.com
- Facebook: Le Lovely Mae Laborte
- Skype: Lei Laborte

# LOVELY MAE LABORTE

Digital Marketing and SEO Specialist

# **Freelance Content Writer**

Lauvette, Exent, Pondr, Beyond Ages | Jan 2019- Dec 2019

- Schedules and writes content in WordPress for blogs and websites of clients
- Creates and checks content for SEO in Yoast
- Manages social media calendar
- Edits the images used for Facebook posts using Photoshop
- Proofreads and assigns writing tasks to other writers.

## EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

#### **Zhejiang Normal University**

MA Public Administration | October 2020 - June 2022 Jinhua, China China Scholarship Council Full Scholarship Awardee Outstanding International Student Awardee

#### University of the Philippines-Diliman

**Certification of Professional Education | 2016-2017**Diliman, Quezon City
University Scholar

#### University of the Philippines-Manila

BA Political Science | 2011-2015 Ermita, Manila University Scholar

## LICENSES/CERTIFICATIONS

Navigating On-Page and Technical SEO: A Semrush Deep Dive Semrush Academy September 19, 2023

Keyword Research with Semrush: A Step-by-Step Guide Semrush Academy September 19, 2023

On-Page and Technical SEO Course Semrush Academy September 18, 2023

SEO Principles: An Essential Guide for Beginners Semrush Academy September 18, 2023

Semrush SEO Crash Course with Brian Dean Semrush Academy September 15, 2023

Licensed Professional Teacher January 19, 2022